Liana van Rensburg

Software Developer





liana.vanrensburg@gmail.com (+64) 027 3445 660 Auckland, New Zealand

I am a focussed, ambitious and highly motivated self-taught developer with a passion for clean code and building beautiful, high performing, efficient software. After 10 years working as a Technical Director in the Visual Effects Industry, across Europe and North America, I pivoted to Tech and have not looked back. 💟

Skills

Programming Languages: C#, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript

.Net, Spring, Flask, ReactJS, MobX, AngularJS, CSS, HTML, Technologies + Frameworks: PostgreSQL, Redis, SignalR, Stripe, Postman, Docker

Project Experience

Laurier:

- Designed and built a **B2C e-commerce** web application for luxury consumer goods.
- Created a multi-project solution using ASP.Net **Core** and a single-page client app using **Angular** and TypeScript.
- **Stripe** for payment processing, **Redis** for storing the shopping cart and PostgreSQL for data persistence.

Eventfriend:

- Designed and built a **fully responsive social** media web application.
- Created a multi-project solution using **ASP.Net Core** and a single-page client app using **React**, TypeScript and React Router. Used MobX for state management
- Live chat function using **SignalR** and Photo upload widget using Cloudinary

Titan:

- Designed and built a **project Management** tool to track and manage projects and team members.
- Built with Java, Spring, Tymeleaf, JavaScript, HTML. CSS
- Data persistence: PostgreSQL database hosted on **AWS**.

Movinest:

- Designed and built a **fully responsive** web application to list and share movies and TV shows
- Access to extensive movie database using themoviedb.org API
- Built with Python, Flask, HTML, CSS.
- Data Persistence: PostgreSQL

Work Experience

Freelance Software Developer:

Oct 2020 - Now Auckland, New Zealand

Lighting Technical Director:

May 2017 - Nov 2019 Framestore Montréal, Canada

Environment Technical Director:

Oct 2015 - May 2017 Framestore Montréal, Canada

Environment Technical Director (Freelance):

Dec 2014 - Jul 2015 MPC Montréal, Canada Aug 2014 - Dec 2014 Weta Digital Wellington, NZ

3D Generalist Technical Director (Freelance):

Dec 2012 - Dec 2013

May 2011 - Nov 2011 Oct 2010 - May 2011 Rocket Science Toronto, Canada Mac Guff Paris, France Passion Pictures London, UK

Education

Mathematics for Machine Learning: Coursera

Design Patterns in C# & .Net Udemy

Data Structures + Algorithms Udemy

Unit Testing for C# Developers Udemy

Bachelor of Fine Arts University of Auckland, NZ